C. Jordan Ball III jordan@cjordanball.info www.cjordanball.info https://github.com/cjordanball www.linkedin.com/in/cjordanball

Software / WebApp Developer

C | Javascript | Node.j | React | Angular | Postgresql | MongoDB

PROFILE

Former attorney turned programmer/web developer, with experience designing and building full-stack web applications in both Node.js/Express and Ruby/Rails. Highly skilled as a problem solver, ranked 3rd out of 40,000+ users on the coderbyte.com coding challenge website. A lifelong learner who combines a love of new technologies with a passion for digging deep into programming fundamentals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS (most developed are bolded)

Programming/Markup Languages: JavaScript, C, Ruby, HTML5, CSS3
Server-Side Frameworks: Node.js, Express.js, Rails, Sails

Front-End Frameworks: React/Flux, Angular.JS, Bootstrap, Iodash, jQuery

Database: MongoDB, Mongoose, **PostgreSQL**, knex

Templating: Jade, ejs
Charting: d3, Highcharts

Testing: Jasmine, mocha

Other: Regular expressions, Git/GitHub, Heroku, npm, Pivotal Tracker,

Gulp, Webpack, Browserify, RequireJS, ES6, agile development

EXPERIENCE

CaseNEX

Aug 2015 to Feb 2016

Software developer on team designing and implementing major commercial web-based application for the education market. Responsible for programming throughout the development stack, including basic design and layout of page components, implementing components using JavaScript/Node.js/jReact.js/Flux, setting up routes in a RESTful routing structure, writing database queries to react with application API, and distributing data as need through a Flux event framework.

Web Developer

March 2015 to July 2015

Developing web apps, primarily using Node.js, Angular.JS, MongoDB and Socket.io.

General Assembly

Nov 2015 to Feb 2016

Full time immersive coding boot camp, building web apps using MEAN stack and Ruby/ Rails framework. Devoted approximately 90 to 100+ hours per week, including class sessions, homework, and building full-scale web applications. Graduated with extensive experience in designing and building web apps from front-end design to server-side and database.

EDUCATION (Degree Programs)

Manhattan School of Music

New York City

Bachelor of Music—Classical Guitar

Georgetown University Law Center

Washington, DC

Juris Doctor

New York University School of Law

New York City

LL.M.—Taxation

C. Jordan Ball III

Software / WebApp Developer

EDUCATION (Other)

Harvard University/edX

Verified Certificate

CS50—Introduction to Computer Science

May 2015

Harvard's gateway computer science course. Although considered one of the most rigorous undergraduate courses at Harvard, it has proved so popular that in 2015 it was adopted by Yale, via lectures streamed from the Harvard campus.

The first two-thirds of this twelve week course are implemented in C, followed by sections addressing the Internet, web applications, and computer security, utilizing PHP, JavaScript, SQL and other common web languages/technologies. Graded assignments consist of nine problem sets plus a final project. Topics covered include: C syntax and programming structures; debugging techniques, particularly use of the gdb debugging tool; analysis and implementation of algorithms, with a focus on asymptotic run times of common searching and sorting algorithms; data structures, including arrays, trees, tries, hash tables, linked lists, queues and stacks; memory allocation and management, including use of pointers, heap and stack memory; and file input/output, both dynamically and at the command line.

Code Fellows Completed

Foundations II: JavaScript October 2014

Survey of the fundamentals of JavaScript, including basics of functional, asynchronous programming, object-oriented JavaScript concepts, AJAX/JSON, use of libraries such as lodash, underscore, jQuery, use of Git/GitHub.

TreeHouse (online courses)

Completed

Git Basics 2014—2015

HTML / HTML Tables / HTML Forms

CSS Basics / CSS—Beyond the Basics / Create a Modal Window with CSS

Ruby Basics

Java Basics

AJAX Basics

Node.js Basics

Build a Simple Dynamic Site with Node.js

Understanding "this" in JavaScript

Egghead.io (online courses)	Completed
React Fundamentals	September 2015
React Flux (using ES6)	Spring 2016
D3	Spring 2016
Angular2 (using TypeScript)	(In progress)

Code School (online courses)

Completed

Shaping Up With Angular.js

Spring 2015

PERSONAL

Music Performance

Classical guitar, viola, violin. Previously performed and recorded with the Tidewater Guitar Orchestra, and member of the Virginia Beach Chamber Players.

Golf

Previously a 3-handicap golfer, although time constraints over the last few years have made my game rather inconsistent.

Reading

Recent titles include Daniel James Brown, *The Boys in the Boat*; Daniel J. Levitin, *This is Your Brain on Music*; Michael Fogus, *Functional JavaScript*; John Resig and Bear Bibeault, *Secrets of the JavaScript Ninja*.